<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Shubham Sharma</title>
    <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Shubham Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/credit_card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/credit_card/</guid>
      <description>Consumers in 2020 reported losing over $3.3 billion to fraud, an increase of $1.5 billion over the amount reported in 2019. Worldwide, businesses are expected to lose $75 billion to e-commerce fraud from 2019 to 2023. In 2019, the U.S. accounted for 33.57 percent of all gross card fraud losses worldwide.
Credit card fraud represented the second most commonly reported type of identity theft in 2020. In 2020, credit cards were most frequently identified as the payment method in fraud reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID 19: Patient Pre-Condition Analysis</title>
      <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/covid/</guid>
      <description>My main objective was to analyze the factors that influence mortality in patients who do not need an intensive care unit and those who do. What are the underlying comorbidities that patients are likely to test positive for COVID? Which factors influence the need for an intensive care unit? This can help with patient triage, optimal distribution of vaccinations (if needed) in countries with limited resources, or prevention in countries susceptible to the virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Bookings Analysis</title>
      <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/hotel_booking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/hotel_booking/</guid>
      <description>The main idea behind this project is to optimize product price and availability for maximum revenue. So, basically the goal is to increase the average daily revenue of a hotel by selling the right product via the right distribution channel, for a reasonable price to a customer.
I analyzed a hotel dataset that consisted of around 120k bookings, with details related to bookings, customer, length of stay, travel agents, distribution channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination Rates in California</title>
      <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/vaccination_rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/vaccination_rates/</guid>
      <description>Conducted the necessary analyses of vaccination rates in California school districts and compared them to the vaccination rates in the US in the past years. Using this study, we might be able to improve the reporting rates and the vaccination rates of the districts by finding out the factors directly affecting the vaccination rate.
 Used RStudio to perform data cleaning, data preprocessing and exploratory data analysis with the help of tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football Database Management System</title>
      <link>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/football_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shsharma14.github.io/portfolio/post/football_database/</guid>
      <description>Designed an Entity Relationship diagram &amp;amp; created a Football leagues database on Microsoft SQL Server management studio. Created views/stored procedures in MS SSMS. Built an app using Microsoft PowerApps.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
